UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
Albert?
앨버트?
What's he doing here?
그 사람 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
-Hello there. -Welcome.
-안녕. -환영.
My word.
내 말.
That's not a car you see in these parts.
이 부분에서 볼 수 있는 자동차는 아닙니다.
I'm running a bit low on fuel.
연료가 조금 부족해요.
Can I get some emergency fuel and an oil change as well?
비상용 연료 좀 구할 수 있을까요? 그리고 오일도 갈아주나요?
We do everything here.
우리는 여기서 모든 일을 합니다.
This is why
이것이 바로 이유이다
you should know your place and not act up.
당신은 당신의 위치를 ​​알고 행동하지 않아야합니다.
I'm not sure if we have engine oil in stock.
잘 모르겠어요 엔진오일 재고가 있는 경우
It might take a few days.
며칠이 걸릴 수도 있습니다.
Take your time.
천천히 시간을 가지세요.
Can you just call me a cab to Seoul?
그냥 서울까지 택시 좀 불러주실 수 있나요?
A cab?
택시?
Hey. I'm calling from Horang.
여기요. 호랑에서 전화가 왔습니다.
Send me a cab.
택시를 보내주세요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
There's…
거기에…
There's a woman there.
거기 여자가 있어요.
You know,
아시다시피,
I've heard of people spotting
사람들이 눈에 띈다는 이야기를 들었습니다
a maiden ghost near that highway.
그 고속도로 근처에 처녀 유령이 있어요.
I'll call you when the car's ready.
차가 준비되면 전화할게요.
Can you leave me your phone number?
전화번호를 남겨주실 수 있나요?
What did you see out there?
거기서 무엇을 보셨나요?
Jeez, that scared me.
이런, 그게 겁이 났어요.
I thought he was just another deadbeat.
나는 그가 또 다른 데드 비트라고 생각했습니다.
Who is he really?
그는 정말로 누구입니까?
It was that bastard in the van who tried to kidnap me.
밴에 있던 그 놈이었어 나를 납치하려던 사람.
Hey.
여기요.
No woman should be there alone this late.
어떤 여자도 이 늦은 시간에 혼자 있어서는 안 됩니다.
Aren't you scared at all?
하나도 안 무서워?
There are still gangsters out there, you know.
아직도 갱스터가 있네 거기 밖에서요.
Don't you know how scary this world is?
이 세상이 얼마나 무서운지 모르시나요?
How could I have known that the van guy was the auto shop owner?
내가 어떻게 알았겠어? 그 밴 남자가 자동차 가게 주인이었다고?
And Albert was supposed to be with his family,
그리고 앨버트는 그래야 했어 그의 가족과 함께,
so how was I to know I'd find him there?
그럼 내가 그 사람을 거기서 찾을 줄 어떻게 알았지?
For all we know, Albert could be managing the slush fund.
우리가 아는 한, Albert가 비자금을 관리하고 있을 수도 있습니다.
He's Chairman Kang's grandson, after all.
그 사람이 바로 강회장 손자거든요.
He's not capable of that though.
하지만 그는 그럴 능력이 없습니다.
Capabilities don't decide how people work.
능력은 사람들이 일하는 방식을 결정하지 않습니다.
They just keep quiet and do as they're told.
그들은 그냥 조용히 지내요 그리고 그 말대로 하세요.
Seeing that you're taking his side, he must've grown on you already.
당신이 그 사람 편을 드는 걸 보니, 그 사람은 이미 당신을 좋아했을 거예요.
Don't be ridiculous!
말도 안되는 소리하지 마세요!
What's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
What are you doing out here?
여기서 뭐하고 있어요?
I was waiting for you.
나는 당신을 기다리고 있었다.
Me? Why?
나? 왜?
I'm about to make you an offer you can't refuse.
내가 당신에게 제안을 하나 하려고 합니다. 당신은 거절할 수 없습니다.
It's cold. Can't we go inside and talk?
춥다. 우리 안으로 들어가서 얘기하면 안 돼요?
Someone might overhear us there.
누군가가 그곳에서 우리의 말을 엿들을 수도 있습니다.
This has to stay between you and me only.
이건 너와 나 사이에만 있어야 해.
I was originally going to do it on my own,
원래는 혼자 하려고 했는데,
but I need your help now that Go Bok-cheol is out.
하지만 네 도움이 필요해 이제 고복철이 나갔으니.
Anyway, let me get to the point.
어쨌든 요점을 말씀드리겠습니다.
There's some easy money at the company.
회사에 돈이 좀 있어요.
What? Money?
무엇? 돈?
Yeah.
응.
I'm thinking of hiring you as a bodyguard-assistant.
나는 당신을 채용할 생각이에요 경호원 보조원으로.
I'll make it worth your while.
나는 그것을 당신의 가치있게 만들 것입니다.
I'm offering you the chance of a lifetime right now.
나는 당신에게 제안하고 있습니다 지금 당장 일생일대의 기회.
Oh gosh!
맙소사!
Hong Jang-mi!
홍장미!
You'll have the RA come running.
RA가 실행되도록 할 것입니다.
You're afraid of her, but not afraid to steal from the company?
당신은 그녀를 두려워합니다 하지만 회사에서 물건을 훔치는 것은 두렵지 않나요?
Hold on.
기다리다.
She definitely knows about the Outstanding Women Club's slush fund.
그녀는 확실히 알고 있어요 우수여성클럽의 비자금입니다.
Maybe she knows about Yehppee and the slush fund ledger as well?
어쩌면 그녀는 Yehppee에 대해 알고 있을지도 몰라 그리고 비자금 장부도요?
This easy money you speak of.
당신이 말하는 이 쉬운 돈.
When and how did you find out about it?
언제, 어떻게 알게 되었나요?
I help Ms. Song out with the Outstanding Women Employees' Club.
나는 송 선생님의 일을 돕습니다. 우수여성직원클럽.
It turns out that was a paid position.
그것은 유료 포지션이었던 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
I'm just seeking compensation for the unauthorized use of my name.
난 그냥 보상을 구하는 중이야 내 이름을 무단으로 사용하는 것에 대해.
How much is it?
얼마입니까?
Is it enough to change your life?
인생을 바꾸는 것만으로도 충분합니까?
What's with that look in her eyes?
그녀의 눈에 보이는 그 표정은 무엇입니까?
Why does it feel like I'm being interrogated?
왜 그런 느낌이 들까? 내가 심문을 받고 있다고요?
You know what I mean.
무슨 말인지 아시겠죠?
After all, you stopped me from going on that business trip.
결국 넌 날 막았어 그 출장을 가는 것부터요.
I haven't even checked the account yet.
아직 계좌도 확인해보지 못했습니다.
It could be one big one?
하나의 큰 것이 될 수 있습니까?
Maybe ten million won?
아마 1000만원 정도?
Queen Bee.
여왕벌.
I'm telling you this because I care about you.
나는 이것을 당신에게 말하고 있습니다. 내가 당신을 걱정하기 때문입니다.
Don't do it.
하지 마세요.
Just promise me you won't, here and now.
지금 여기서 그러지 않겠다고 약속해주세요.
What's with the straight face?
꼿꼿한 얼굴은 어쩌고?
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
Happy now?
이제 행복해?
I can't trust Go Bok-hee, and Albert seems suspicious.
고복희를 믿을 수 없다. 그리고 앨버트는 의심스러운 것 같아요.
This is driving me crazy.
이것이 나를 미치게 만든다.
Damn it!
젠장!
EPISODE 7: I KNOW WHAT YOU DID LAST SUMMER
에피소드 7: 나는 네가 지난 여름에 무슨 일을 했는지 알고 있다
Good morning.
좋은 아침입니다.
Did you have a good time with your family last night?
즐거운 시간 보내셨나요? 어젯밤에 가족들과 함께?
Of course.
물론.
The coffee smells great.
커피 냄새가 좋아요.
I'll take one as well.
나도 하나 가져갈게.
Was that crossing the line?
선을 넘은거였어?
You crossed way over the line.
당신은 선을 넘었습니다.
How does a young kid like you
어린 애가 어떻게 널 좋아해?
think you can ask someone clearly your senior to make you coffee?
누군가에게 물어볼 수 있을 것 같아 분명히 선배가 너한테 커피 만들어 줄 거지?
Don't you have working hands?
일하는 손이 없나요?
She's not older than me. I'm…
그녀는 나보다 나이가 많지 않습니다. 나는…
-I'm her senior. -Big Al.
-내가 그 사람 선배예요. -빅 알.
You're coming to the division head lunch, right?
당신이 온다 부서장 점심 먹으러 가죠?
You'd better not exclude him just because he's young.
그 사람을 배제하지 않는 게 좋을 거야 단지 그 사람이 어리니까.
Bring him along.
그를 데리고 오세요.
Take me out of here right now.
지금 당장 나를 여기서 꺼내주세요.
-Oh, right now? -Yes.
-아, 지금요? -예.
This way.
이쪽으로.
Is that young man really a division manager?
그 청년인가? 정말 부서장인가요?
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
He's the chairman's grandson.
회장의 손자입니다.
Miss!
놓치다!
You should've told me sooner!
좀 더 일찍 말했어야 했는데!
Seriously?
진지하게?
How is his desk so empty?
그의 책상은 어쩜 그리 비어있나요?
What are you doing over there, Ms. Hong?
홍 선생님, 거기서 뭐 하세요?
This videotape stack fell from the desk.
이 비디오테이프 더미가 책상에서 떨어졌습니다.
Gosh, Mr. Oh should tidy up a little.
맙소사, 오 선생님은 좀 정리를 하셔야 할 것 같아요.
This is a report on Kang Myeong-hwi's car accident.
에 관한 보고서입니다. 강명휘 교통사고.
Why was this…
왜 그랬지…
TRAFFIC ACCIDENT FATALITY INCIDENT REPORT
교통사고 사망사고 보고서
6. ACTIONS TAKEN FOLLOW-UP INVESTIGATION
6. 취해진 조치 후속 조사
7. NOTES: VEHICLE INSPECTION ON DAY BEFORE ACCIDENT
7. 참고 사항: 차량 검사 사고 전날
At Horang Auto Repair Shop?
호랑자동차정비소에서요?
Did you see the article
기사 보셨나요?
about the bankruptcy status of the top 50 conglomerates?
파산상태에 대해서 50대 대기업 중?
What's your outlook, President Shin?
신 회장님의 전망은 어떻습니까?
"The exchange rate is in crisis, and domestic demand has plunged."
"환율이 위기에 빠졌습니다. 국내 수요도 급락했다”고 말했다.
The media reports are stirring market sentiment.
언론 보도 시장 심리를 자극하고 있습니다.
However,
그러나,
since pension funds announced up to one trillion won in market injections,
연금기금이 발표된 이후 시장 투입 1조원,
I believe the likelihood of Korea facing a Southeast Asian-style crisis is low.
나는 한국이 직면할 가능성을 믿는다. 동남아시아식 위기는 낮다.
As expected,
예상대로,
it seems our perspectives align.
우리의 관점이 일치하는 것 같습니다.
Both crises and opportunities are illusions.
두 위기 모두 기회는 환상입니다.
Just keep your eye on the prize.
상금을 계속 주시하십시오.
Use anything you can,
가능한 모든 것을 활용하세요.
whether it's a sense of crisis or patriotism,
그게 감각인지 위기나 애국심,
to sell as much as possible.
최대한 많이 팔려고.
-Yes, sir. -Understood.
- 네, 선생님. -이해했다.
Don't worry, sir.
걱정하지 마세요.
What should we name the fund?
펀드 이름을 뭘로 해야 할까요?
You do know that Hanmin was named after
한민의 이름이 한민이라는 걸 아시죠?
the characters that make up "Republic of Korea," right?
구성하는 캐릭터들 '대한민국' 맞죠?
All right then.
그럼요.
Let's see here.
여기서 봅시다.
There.
거기.
Look.
바라보다.
"New Korea." That's perfect.
"뉴코리아." 완벽해요.
NEW KOREA
뉴코리아
NEW KOREA FUND
뉴코리아펀드
INVEST IN KOREA'S NEXT LEAP FORWARD!
대한민국의 새로운 도약을 위해 투자하세요!
HANMIN'S TOP-SELLING INVESTMENT FUND NEW KOREA FUND
한민의 최고 판매 투자 펀드 뉴코리아펀드
Attention, everyone.
모두들 주목하세요.
We've received a new directive from the head office.
우리는 새로운 지시를 받았습니다 본사에서.
The top New Korea Fund salesperson
뉴코리아펀드 최고영업사원
will receive a performance bonus at the end of the year.
성과 보너스를 받게 됩니다 연말에.
Here's to another productive day.
또 다른 생산적인 하루를 보내세요.
All right, get ready for the chant!
좋아, 노래할 준비를 해라!
Let's once again survive today!
오늘도 한번 살아남자!
Let's survive as long as we can!
최대한 오래 살아남자!
Beyond the Han River!
한강 너머!
-To the World! To the Future! Hanmin!
-세계로! 미래를 향해! 한민!
Let's give it our all today.
오늘은 우리의 모든 것을 바쳐보자.
TODAY'S TOP INVESTMENT PICKS:
오늘의 최고 투자 종목:
NEW KOREA FUND
뉴코리아펀드
It's called the New Korea Fund,
신한국기금이라고 합니다.
and it's the top-selling investment fund from the industry-leading Hanmin.
그리고 그것은 가장 많이 팔리는 투자 펀드입니다 업계를 선도하는 한민에서.
You'll see here that you're guaranteed a 30% return.
여기서 보시죠 30% 수익을 보장받는다고 합니다.
It's a fund that prioritizes stability alongside returns.
최우선으로 생각하는 펀드입니다 수익률과 함께 안정성.
Is the annual return really 30%?
연수익률이 정말 30%인가요?
Of course. It's all guaranteed.
물론. 모두 보장됩니다.
NEW KOREA FUND KIM MI-SOOK
뉴코리아펀드 김미숙
Breakfast is ready, everyone.
아침 식사가 준비되었습니다 여러분.
Look at all these expensive, imported bananas…
이 비싼 것 좀 보세요. 수입바나나...
All of it looks expensive.
다 비싸 보이는데요.
I got them on a recent visit to my relatives.
최근 방문에서 받았어요 내 친척들에게.
Jang-mi, come and eat breakfast!
장미야, 와서 아침 먹어!
Okay.
좋아요.
Mi-sook, what is all this?
미숙아 이게 다 뭐야?
It's the promotion period for the New Korea Fund,
프로모션 기간이에요 새한국기금을 위해,
so I'm making these for the clients.
그래서 저는 고객들을 위해 이것을 만들고 있어요.
I want to do well with this so I can get a permanent spot next year.
이걸로 잘하고 싶다 그래서 내년에는 영구 자리를 얻을 수 있어요.
Here's a pick-me-up treat for you.
여기 당신을 위한 간식이 있습니다.
I am Kim Mi-sook from Hanmin's Magang Branch.
나는 김미숙이다 한민 마강지점에서
You're already starting the day with a sales pitch.
벌써 하루가 시작됐네요 판매 안내와 함께.
You'd better sell her one, Jang-mi.
장미씨한테 하나 파는 게 나을 것 같아요.
Did it sound okay?
괜찮은 것 같나요?
SPECIAL BENEFITS FOR NEW CLIENTS
신규 고객을 위한 특별 혜택
INVESTMENT KEY POINTS EXPLANATION CHECKLIST FOR SALESPERSONS
투자 핵심 포인트 설명 영업사원을 위한 체크리스트
Ms. Kim.
김 씨.
Don't you think you're pushing too hard for that performance bonus?
너무 세게 밀고 있다고 생각하지 않니? 그 성과 보너스를 위해?
Take it easy.
진정하세요.
I'll make us look bad if you go overboard.
너무 지나치게 하면 우리를 안 좋게 보이게 만들 거예요.
But you know how expensive housing is in Seoul.
하지만 당신은 알고 있습니다 서울 집값이 얼마나 비싼지.
I hope you understand that I need this.
이것이 필요하다는 것을 이해하시기 바랍니다.
Sure.
확신하는.
We should all work hard.
우리 모두 열심히 일해야 합니다.
Yeah, good luck.
응, 행운을 빈다.
I guess we should do our best.
우리는 최선을 다해야 할 것 같아요.
Mi-sook.
미숙.
You're coming home late.
집에 늦게 오시네요.
I had some business to take care of after everyone left.
나한테는 처리할 일이 좀 있었어 모두가 떠난 후.
Do you always pack your lunch and dinner?
점심, 저녁은 항상 포장하시나요?
Eating out near the office is expensive,
사무실 근처에서 외식을 하려면 가격이 비싸고,
so I'm trying to save on expenses.
그래서 비용을 절약하려고 노력 중이에요.
Mi-sook, let's switch.
미숙아, 바꿔보자.
-What? -I bought some snacks for Bom.
-무엇? -봄이한테 간식을 좀 샀어요.
I bet she'll love them more if they come from you.
나는 그녀가 그들을 더 사랑할 것이라고 확신한다 그들이 당신에게서 온다면.
She's a mommy's girl, after all.
결국 그녀는 엄마의 딸입니다.
It feels like I'm in high school again,
다시 고등학생이 된 것 같은 느낌,
lunchbox in hand and linking arms with a close friend.
손에 도시락 그리고 친한 친구와 팔짱을 끼는 것.
I've been hoping we could be friends for a while now.
나는 바랐다 우리는 이제 한동안 친구가 될 수 있을 것 같아요.
SLUSH FUND CUSTODIANS
비자금 관리인
FARMERS' BANK, CHUNGSEO BRANCH
농민은행 청서지점
CHUNGSEO BANK
청서은행
SAENARA BANK, CHUNGSEO BRANCH
새나라은행 청서지점
Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미.
Try as you might, but I won't give up on this money.
가능한 한 노력해 보세요. 하지만 나는 이 돈을 포기하지 않을 것이다.
I'll be fine on my own.
나는 혼자서 괜찮을 것이다.
Now serving customer number 20.
현재 20번 고객에게 서비스를 제공하고 있습니다.
I'm here to withdraw.
나는 철수하러 왔습니다.
Ma'am, the account is empty.
부인, 계좌가 비어있습니다.
It was withdrawn by an authorized user.
승인된 사용자에 의해 철회되었습니다.
What?
무엇?
Print me the statement.
명세서를 인쇄해 주세요.
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
WITHDRAWN BY AUTHORIZED USER
승인된 사용자에 의한 철회
WITHDRAWAL: 5 BILLION WON REMAINING BALANCE: 0 WON
출금 : 50억원 남은 잔액: 0원
Do you remember who it was, like anything distinctive?
누구였는지 기억하시나요? 뭔가 독특한 것 같은?
Well, the thing is…
글쎄, 문제는…
Start talking if you don't want things to escalate.
말하기 시작 상황이 확대되는 것을 원하지 않는 경우.
Right now.
지금 바로.
Well…
음…
A man came by just a moment ago.
조금 전에 한 남자가 찾아왔습니다.
A man?
남자?
OUTSTANDING WOMAN AWARD NOTICE
뛰어난 여성상 공지
Ms. Hong.
홍 선생님.
Congratulations!
축하해요!
This quarter's Outstanding Woman is Hong Jang-mi!
이번 분기 뛰어난 여성 홍장미입니다!
Really?
정말?
RECIPIENT: HONG JANG-MI, RISK MANAGEMENT DIVISION
수신자: 홍장미 리스크관리부서
It's all thanks to us, really.
다 우리 덕분이에요, 정말.
Your productivity is the result of our guidance and direction.
귀하의 생산성이 곧 결과입니다 우리의 지도와 방향.
That's how you want to take credit?
그게 당신이 신용을 얻고 싶은 방법인가요?
Treat us to dinner.
저녁을 대접해 주세요.
You've reached Risk Management.
위험 관리에 도달했습니다.
This is Song Ju-ran.
송주란 입니다.
Did you check the intranet announcement?
인트라넷 공지사항은 확인하셨나요?
Yes, I just did.
네, 방금 했어요.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Can you come to my office with a copy of your ID and bankbook?
내 사무실로 와줄 수 있니? 신분증과 통장 사본을 갖고 계십니까?
Yes, ma'am. I'll be right there.
네, 부인. 바로 거기 갈게요.
May I ask
물어봐도 될까요?
what you're doing here, Mr. Oh?
여기서 뭐 하시는 거예요, 오 씨?
As her immediate supervisor,
그녀의 직속 상사로서,
I'm here to congratulate, take photos, and deliver flowers.
축하해주려고 왔어요 사진도 찍고, 꽃도 배달하고.
Shall we start with photos?
사진부터 시작해볼까요?
Sure.
확신하는.
All right.
괜찮은.
Here we go.
여기 있습니다.
One, two, three.
하나 둘 셋.
That's going to be great. One more.
정말 좋을 것 같아요. 하나 더.
Here we go. One, two…
여기 있습니다. 하나, 둘…
That's so great.
정말 훌륭해요.
Okay.
좋아요.
No.
아니요.
Ms. Song,
송씨,
you take this.
너는 이것을 가져라.
Please.
제발.
Another one?
또 하나?
Smile.
웃다.
Should I just confront him?
그냥 그 사람과 맞서야 할까요?
No, he might just deny it.
아니, 그냥 부정할 수도 있다.
Would he really have recommended me knowing that the OW Club
그 사람이 정말 나를 추천했을까? OW 클럽인 줄 알고
is a money-laundering scheme?
돈세탁 계획인가요?
It's all thanks to your recommendation.
모두 여러분의 추천 덕분입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You can thank me with a tasty dinner.
맛있는 저녁 식사로 나에게 감사할 수 있어요.
I can do that.
나는 그것을 할 수 있다.
I should deliver the happy news to the others.
배달해야지 다른 사람들에게 기쁜 소식을 전합니다.
No, wait.
아니, 잠깐만요.
We should have dinner,
우리 저녁 먹어야지,
just the two of us.
우리 둘만.
My roommates told me
룸메이트들이 나한테 말했어
that President Shin's predecessor, President Kang Myeong-hwi,
신 회장의 전임자다. 강명휘 회장님,
was your maternal uncle.
너의 외삼촌이었어.
Yeah, he was.
응, 그랬지.
I think I read about his traffic accident in the paper.
내가 읽은 것 같아 그의 교통사고가 신문에 나왔어요.
It caused quite a stir.
그것은 상당한 파문을 일으켰습니다.
But he was replaced, and the company just went back to business as usual,
하지만 그는 교체되었고 회사는 방금 평소처럼 사업에 복귀했습니다.
as if nothing happened.
마치 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 것처럼.
It's like they swapped out a missing part.
누락된 부품을 교체한 것과 같습니다.
It's weird.
이상해요.
Were you and your uncle close?
당신과 당신의 삼촌은 가까웠나요?
It was one-sided.
일방적이었습니다.
He loved me very much.
그는 나를 매우 사랑했습니다.
He used to prattle on about the company and numbers,
그 사람은 수다를 떨곤 했어 회사와 숫자에 대해,
none of which I understood.
나는 그 어느 것도 이해하지 못했습니다.
-"Numbers"? -Yeah.
-"숫자"? -응.
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Was it a week before the accident?
사고 일주일 전이었나?
He told me…
그는 나에게 말했다…
After work, I wanted to pick up some chicken skewers to go.
퇴근하고 픽업하고 싶었는데 닭꼬치 좀 가져가세요.
And I just happened to run into Mr. Shin out front,
그리고 방금 우연히 앞에서 신씨를 만나다
totally by chance.
완전 우연히.
I heard this place is good.
여기가 좋다고 들었어.
You, me, Bok-hee, Mi-sook, and Bo…
너, 나, 복희, 미숙, 보…
There are 5 of us, so I'll take 50 to go, ma'am!
우리는 5명이고, 그러니 50분을 가져가겠습니다, 부인!
50 SKEWERS
꼬치 50개
Did you say 50?
50이라고 했나?
That's going to take some time.
시간이 좀 걸릴 것 같아요.
You should join us for a quick drink while you wait.
너도 우리와 함께 빨리 한잔해야 해 기다리는 동안.
Shut up.
입 다물어.
What reason do you two have to meet outside the office?
두 분은 무슨 이유가 있으신가요? 사무실 밖에서 만나려고?
I was having a one-on-one with my immediate supervisor.
일대일로 하고 있었는데 내 직속 상사와 함께.
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
Let me pour you a drink.
음료수를 부어 드리겠습니다.
Ms. Hong.
홍 선생님.
If you hate him, just say so.
그 사람이 싫다면 그냥 그렇게 말하세요.
What's with the foam party?
거품 파티가 뭐죠?
It's fine. I enjoy foam.
괜찮습니다. 나는 거품을 즐긴다.
I guess you enjoy drinking.
술을 즐기시는 것 같아요.
You didn't turn down a single drink at the last company dinner either.
넌 술 한 잔도 거절하지 않았어 회사 마지막 회식에서도.
My ex-girlfriend could hold her liquor and enjoyed drinking.
내 전 여자친구는 술을 마실 수도 있었어 그리고 술을 즐겼다.
I forced myself to drink more after I broke up with her,
억지로 더 마셨는데 그 사람과 헤어진 후,
just to see how it felt.
그냥 어떤 느낌인지 알아보려고요.
And how did it feel?
그리고 기분이 어땠나요?
It was nothing special.
특별한 것은 아니었습니다.
I'll stand down today.
오늘은 물러나겠습니다.
You're not the least bit helpful.
당신은 조금도 도움이 되지 않습니다.
-The skewers to go are ready. -Okay.
- 갈 꼬치는 준비되어 있어요. -좋아요.
-Let's go.
-갑시다.
Let's go before they get cold.
추워지기 전에 가자.
We'll be going now.
이제 갈게요.
Future uncle-in-law.
미래의 삼촌.
You should be careful in Yeouido.
여의도에서는 조심하셔야 합니다.
There are too many prying eyes.
엿보는 눈이 너무 많습니다.
Isn't it more inappropriate to meet privately with a subordinate?
더 부적절하지 않나요 부하 직원과 개인적으로 만나려고?
I'd like it to be inappropriate,
부적절했으면 좋겠는데,
but I haven't figured out a way yet.
하지만 아직 방법을 찾지 못했습니다.
In other words, there's nothing remotely improper going on between us.
즉, 아무것도 없다. 우리 사이에 원격으로 부적절한 일이 일어나고 있습니다.
For now, at least.
적어도 지금은.
How did you know about the street stall?
노점상을 어떻게 알았나요?
It used to be my ex-girlfriend's favorite spot,
예전에는 그랬어 전여친이 제일 좋아하는 곳,
so I used to come often, all the time.
그래서 자주 오곤 했어요, 항상.
Excuse me then.
그럼 실례합니다.
The weak currency has pushed up prices of grains,
약한 통화 곡물 가격을 인상시켰고,
coffee, and snack foods across the board.
커피와 스낵 식품이 전반적으로 존재합니다.
Gasoline prices have broken above the 843-won-per-liter mark.
휘발유 가격이 이상으로 올랐습니다. 리터당 843원.
"Broken above"?
"위가 깨졌습니다"?
BREAK ABOVE: TO RISE PAST A SPECIFIC LIMIT
Break Above: 특정 한계를 넘어서는 것
With the dismal exchange rate--
처참한 환율로-
"Break above."
"위에서 휴식을 취하세요."
We're back.
우리는 돌아왔다.
Something smells tasty.
뭔가 맛있는 냄새가 난다.
Tonight, we'll be having a chicken skewer party!
오늘 밤 우리는 닭꼬치 파티!
I'm so happy, so excited!
정말 기쁘고 신난다!
Bom, are you happy? How many do you want?
봄아, 행복하니? 몇 개를 원하시나요?
You screwed me over, Hong Jang-mi.
날 망쳤어, 홍장미.
Why did she grill me like that the other night?
그 사람은 왜 나를 그렇게 구웠나요? 저번 밤에?
She must be hiding something.
그녀는 뭔가를 숨기고 있는 게 틀림없어요.
Then I'm going to eat 40!
그럼 40개 먹겠습니다!
The liquidity shortages among second-tier merchant banks
유동성 부족 제2종 종합은행 중에서
have led to a rapid rise in call borrowing.
급격한 상승을 가져왔습니다 콜빌리지 중.
Merchant banks appear to have increased call borrowing
가맹점 등장 콜 차입을 늘렸다
from insurance companies and securities firms,
보험 회사에서 그리고 증권사,
following a sharp decline in funding from bank trusts.
자금의 급격한 감소로 인해 은행 신탁에서.
This merchant banking crisis is more acute in foreign currencies.
이번 머천트뱅킹 위기 외화에서는 더욱 심각하다.
With our two-year corporate bonds maturing in the third week of December,
2년 만기 회사채가 만기되면서 12월 셋째 주,
our funding
우리의 자금
remains tight.
꽉 남아있습니다.
How much?
얼마나 많이?
The issuance amount is projected at 100 billion won.
발행금액 1000억 원으로 예상된다.
That leaves a shortfall of approximately 40 billion won.
그로 인해 부족함이 남습니다 약 400억원 규모다.
What if we raise short-term funds in Myeongdong?
올리면 어떨까? 명동에 단기자금?
We've already pulled in about 20 billion won from there.
우리는 이미 참여했습니다. 거기에서 약 200억 원 정도.
That's quite the display of business prowess.
정말 디스플레이네요 사업능력의.
All these brains in here, and not one can find a source of funds?
여기 있는 모든 두뇌들, 자금 출처를 찾을 수 없습니까?
There is a way, sir.
방법이 있습니다 선생님
Perhaps you could consider freeing up your personal funds.
아마도 당신은 고려할 수 있습니다 개인 자금을 확보합니다.
Why would I do that?
내가 왜 그럴까요?
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Right.
오른쪽.
A personal capital injection by the chairman
개인 자본 투입 회장에 의한
or borrowing against company real estate will only spark rumors.
또는 회사 부동산을 담보로 대출을 받거나 소문만 촉발할 뿐입니다.
There is a market where ultra-short-term funding
시장이 있다 초단기 자금이 있는 곳
can be borrowed using Hanmin's bonds as collateral.
빌릴 수 있다 한민채권을 담보로 사용하고 있습니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
We must fill the granary before winter comes.
우리는 곡물창고를 채워야 한다 겨울이 오기 전에.
Borrow to the limit.
한도까지 빌리세요.
-Yes, sir. -Good.
- 네, 선생님. -좋은.
Hanmin's two-year corporate bonds mature
한민 2년 만기 회사채 만기
in the third week of December,
12월 셋째 주,
but there's no cash for the payouts.
하지만 지불금을 지불할 현금이 없습니다.
So,
그래서,
I've suggested funding through repurchase agreements.
펀딩을 제안했어요 환매 계약을 통해.
Okay. He'll have no choice but to accept our offer later.
좋아요. 그 사람은 선택의 여지가 없을 거예요 하지만 나중에 우리 제안을 받아들이기로 했어요.
I'll send you the preliminary report next week.
내가 보내줄게 다음 주에 예비 보고서를 제출하겠습니다.
Bye.
안녕.
You've reached Shin Jung-woo.
신정우 님에게 도달했습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
It's me, Executive Director Oh Deok-gyu.
저입니다. 오덕규 전무이사 입니다.
How about having lunch with me today?
오늘 나랑 같이 점심 먹는 게 어때?
Unfortunately, I have plans.
불행히도 나에겐 계획이 있다.
I think you'd appreciate meeting these people.
내 생각엔 네가 고마워할 것 같아 이런 사람들을 만나는 것.
They're from the FSS.
FSS 출신이에요.
I'm supposed to have lunch with them today.
점심을 먹기로 했어 오늘 그들과 함께.
I see.
알겠어요.
What time should I meet you?
몇 시에 만나면 될까요?
I'm about to finish this whole pot.
나는 이 냄비 전체를 곧 끝내려고 합니다.
They asked to meet at noon. Where are they?
그들은 정오에 만나자고 했습니다. 그들은 어디에 있나요?
They're busy people.
바쁜 사람들이에요.
And I'm not?
그리고 나는 그렇지 않습니까?
I'm glad you finally changed your mind after being so reluctant.
마침내 마음이 바뀌어서 기뻐요 너무 꺼려진 후에.
Life's better when we help each other out.
우리가 서로 도울 때 삶은 더 좋아집니다.
You only dragged me here because you knew you weren't enough.
넌 나만 여기로 끌고 왔잖아 왜냐하면 당신은 당신이 충분하지 않다는 것을 알았기 때문입니다.
Come on now.
지금 어서.
I've seen plenty of people in Yeouido with that mindset
여의도에서 사람 많이 봤는데 그 마음가짐으로
be swept away by the Han River current.
한강물에 휩쓸려 가다.
Come on, the river can't sweep me away
어서, 강은 나를 쓸어버릴 수 없어
if I'm sitting in the lap of luxury.
내가 호화로운 자리에 앉아 있다면.
Gosh, sorry we're late.
이런, 늦어서 미안해요.
Goodness me.
맙소사.
No need to apologize. We just got here ourselves.
사과할 필요는 없습니다. 우리는 방금 여기에 도착했습니다.
Hello, I'm Shin Jung-woo.
안녕하세요 신정우 입니다.
I'm Director Yun Jae-beom from the FSS.
금감원 윤재범 과장입니다.
I believe we met briefly in your office last time.
잠깐 만났던 것 같은데 저번에 네 사무실에서.
I was unfortunately a bit unwell that day.
안타깝게도 그날 몸이 좀 안 좋았습니다.
Are you better now?
이제 나아졌나요?
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
Gosh, you're much taller than I remember.
맙소사, 당신은 내가 기억하는 것보다 훨씬 더 크군요.
Jeez, it's like a meeting of the in-laws.
이런, 마치 시댁 식구들의 모임 같군요.
Director Yun, you're looking at him as if he's your son-in-law.
윤 감독님, 보고 계시네요 마치 그 사람이 당신의 사위인 것처럼요.
My goodness, he might as well be.
맙소사, 그 사람도 그럴 수도 있겠네요.
Gosh.
이런.
You have such big hands, and you're so tall.
손이 이렇게 크시다니, 그리고 당신은 키가 너무 크네요.
And your nose… Never mind.
그리고 코도… 신경쓰지 마세요.
What a handsome man you are.
당신은 정말 잘 생긴 남자입니다.
Any parent with a daughter would say the same.
딸을 둔 부모라면 누구나 같은 말을 할 것입니다.
But sir, you have two sons.
그런데 선생님, 아들이 둘 있어요.
Hello, I'm Nam Dong-gi.
안녕하세요 남동기 입니다.
Yes, hello.
네, 안녕하세요.
Please sit.
앉으세요.
Please.
제발.
Director Yun, you've become such a lightweight now.
윤 감독님, 당신은 이렇게 됐어요 지금은 너무 가벼워요.
This body of mine can't keep up.
이 몸이 따라가지 못해요.
I would've shown him no mercy
나는 그에게 자비를 베풀지 않았을 것이다
if I were still at the Ministry of Finance and Economy.
내가 아직 있었다면 재정경제부에서.
I've heard Hanmin and the FSS are deeply at odds.
한민이한테 들었어 FSS는 매우 상충됩니다.
A few months ago,
몇 달 전,
there was a search and seizure over slush fund allegations, right?
수색과 압수가 있었다 비자금 의혹 때문이지?
Oh that?
아 그거요?
There was a bit of a misunderstanding.
약간의 오해가 있었습니다.
Wasn't that done by one of your peers, Mr. Nam?
그거 끝난거 아니었어? 당신 동료 남씨가요?
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
She was demoted and transferred to Jeonju,
강등되어 전주로 전근하게 되었고,
and I doubt she'll ever be able to return to headquarters.
그리고 나는 그녀가 그럴 수 있을지 의심스럽다 본부로 돌아가려고.
If only she could take this chance to drop that "Witch of Yeouido" title
그녀가 이 기회를 잡을 수만 있다면 '여의도의 마녀' 타이틀을 떨어뜨리려고
and get married.
그리고 결혼하세요.
Some bide their time to sharpen their knife.
일부는 시간을 기다린다 칼을 갈기 위해.
She may be planning to avenge her humiliation, no?
그녀는 계획 중일 수도 있습니다 그녀의 굴욕에 대한 복수를 위해서죠, 그렇죠?
Come on now. Revenge isn't a one-man sport.
지금 어서. 복수는 혼자서 하는 스포츠가 아닙니다.
Hong Keum-bo doesn't have anyone in her corner,
홍금보가 없네 그녀 구석에 있는 누구든지,
our office included.
우리 사무실도 포함됐어.
And was it ten years ago?
그리고 10년 전이었나?
Everyone at her accounting firm cut ties with her after she was fired.
그녀의 회계법인에 있는 모든 사람들 그녀가 해고된 후 그녀와의 관계를 끊습니다.
I heard even her boyfriend dumped her.
심지어 그녀의 남자친구도 그녀를 차버렸다고 들었습니다.
You gentlemen all get it, don't you?
여러분, 모두 아시죠?
What do we get exactly?
우리는 정확히 무엇을 얻나요?
I don't get it at all.
전혀 이해가 안 돼요.
Right, you might not.
그렇지 않을 수도 있습니다.
You will, once you experience her firsthand.
당신은, 일단 그녀를 직접 경험해 보세요.
President Shin,
신 대표님,
aren't you and Inspector Hong university alumni?
너랑 홍 경위 아니냐? 대학 동창?
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Weren't you the one who offered her a job at the FSS, Director Yun?
그녀에게 제안한 사람은 당신이 아니었나요? 윤국장은 금감원에 취직?
What? Really?
무엇? 정말?
Man, that's top-secret intel that even my wife doesn't know about.
아, 그건 일급비밀 정보야 그건 내 아내도 모르는 일이다.
You're quite impressive.
당신은 정말 인상적이군요.
Shall we arrange for a meeting?
우리 회의를 준비할까요?
I do wonder
정말 궁금하다
what Hong Keum-bo's been up to and what's been on her mind.
홍금보가 무슨 짓을 했는지 그리고 그녀의 마음 속에 무엇이 있었는지.
Sounds good. I'll be waiting for your call.
좋은 것 같아요. 나는 당신의 전화를 기다리고 있습니다.
Damn it.
젠장.
I can't dig properly because I keep getting interrupted.
제대로 파지도 못해요 왜냐면 내가 계속 방해를 받거든요.
I should've just ended him over the skewers.
그냥 그를 끝냈어야 했는데 꼬치 위에.
I see you still visit the emergency stairs to blow off steam at work.
아직도 비상계단을 방문하는 것 같던데 직장에서 스트레스를 날려버리기 위해.
You hired someone for a background check?
신원조사를 위해 누군가를 고용했나요?
I guess dirty tricks are what got you up that ladder.
내 생각에 더러운 속임수는 무엇이 당신을 그 사다리에 올라오게 했는지요.
Why haven't you gotten anywhere, while I've come this far?
왜 아무데도 안 갔어? 내가 여기까지 온 동안?
What?
무엇?
When you let Yun Jae-beom talk you into whistleblowing,
윤재범을 시키면 내부고발을 하라고 얘기해
your life went off the rails.
당신의 인생은 궤도를 벗어났습니다.
You don't have a single ally at the FSS, do you?
너에겐 동맹이 하나도 없어 FSS에서요?
That punk who claimed to be your peer jumped at the chance to smear you.
네 동료라고 주장한 그 새끼 당신을 더럽힐 기회에 뛰어들었습니다.
How exactly does my off-the-rails life and smeared name concern you?
나의 비일상적인 삶은 정확히 어떻게 되는가? 그리고 번진 이름이 당신을 걱정합니까?
President Shin.
신 회장님.
You appear quite intoxicated by your rise in social status,
너 꽤 취한 것 같아 사회적 지위가 높아지면서
and by all means, progress away.
그리고 꼭 나아가십시오.
I'm just doing my job.
나는 단지 내 일을 하고 있을 뿐입니다.
So you'll cling to a sense of justice
그래서 당신은 정의감에 집착하게 될 것입니다
that gets you no recognition and no reward?
그게 당신을 얻는다 인정도 없고 보상도 없나요?
Do you still believe in people after all I put you through?
아직도 사람을 믿나요 결국 내가 당신을 통과시켰나요?
I learned it all from you.
나는 당신에게서 모든 것을 배웠습니다.
You're staying quiet despite having the power to kick me out
조용히 지내는구나 나를 쫓아낼 힘이 있음에도 불구하고
because it could hurt you, no?
너한테 상처를 줄 수도 있으니까, 그렇지?
Because you fear the ever-wary chairman might dig into us?
당신이 두려워하기 때문에 항상 경계심이 강한 회장이 우리를 파헤칠 수도 있나요?
Do you still not get it?
아직도 이해가 안 되시나요?
This is no time for make-believe. "The Witch of Yeouido"?
지금은 꾸며낼 때가 아닙니다. '여의도의 마녀'?
The end for a witch is either exile or death.
마녀의 최후 추방 아니면 죽음이다.
Then just sit back and watch,
그럼 그냥 앉아서 지켜보세요.
just like you did nine years ago.
9년 전에 그랬던 것처럼.
Why were you even there?
왜 거기 있었나요?
Why else?
왜 또?
I went because I was curious about Shin Jung-woo.
내가 갔기 때문에 신정우에 대해 궁금했다.
Man, he was even better in person.
아, 그는 개인적으로 훨씬 더 나았습니다.
He's so tall.
그 사람 키가 너무 크거든요.
That punk is unreal.
그 펑크는 비현실적입니다.
No wonder the invincible Hong Keum-bo melted away
당연하지 무적의 홍금보가 녹아내렸다
like spring snow in early March…
3월초 봄눈처럼…
Director Yun!
윤 감독님!
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
he knew that I was the one who offered you a job at the FSS.
그 사람은 내가 그 사람인 걸 알았어 당신에게 FSS에 일자리를 제안한 사람.
He did?
그랬나요?
How did he know about that?
그는 그것을 어떻게 알았습니까?
Exactly.
정확히.
That happened a long time after you two broke up.
그런 일은 오랜 시간 동안 일어났습니다 너희 둘이 헤어진 후에.
Anyway, I confirmed the deposit in Hong Jang-mi's name.
아무튼 입금 확인했어요 홍장미 이름으로.
The whole 24 billion won came in.
모두 240억 원이 들어갔습니다.
If that's just a part of it,
그것도 일부분이라면,
how much do you think the slush fund is in total?
당신은 얼마나 생각하세요? 비자금이 전부인가요?
ACCOUNT TRANSACTION HISTORY
계정 거래 내역
That OW money must be in Hong Jang-mi's account now,
그 OW 돈이 들어가야 해 지금 홍장미 계정은,
now that she's got the award.
이제 그녀가 상을 받았으니까요.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
I still have this golden goose in the making.
나는 아직도 이 황금 거위를 만들고 있어요.
LONESOME: FEELING LONELY IN A DESOLATE WAY
LONESOME: 쓸쓸하고 외로움을 느끼는 것
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
WOMEN'S MAGAZINE
여성 매거진
Kiddo.
키도.
-Yes?
-예?
Yes, you two.
응, 너희 둘.
Mi-sook is working late tonight, so give Bom her bath.
미숙 씨는 오늘 밤 늦게까지 일해요. 그러니 봄에게 목욕을 시켜주세요.
Okay. Let's go, Bom.
좋아요. 가자, 봄.
Okay.
좋아요.
Bom, did you go outside?
봄아, 밖에 나갔어?
No, I didn't.
아니요, 그렇지 않았습니다.
You must get bored being here alone after everyone leaves for work.
여기 혼자 있으면 심심하겠지 모두 출근한 후.
I feel lonesome.
나는 외로움을 느낀다.
Do you know what that means?
그게 무슨 뜻인지 아시나요?
"Feeling lonely in a desolate way."
"황량한 곳에서 외로움을 느낀다."
That's what the dictionary says.
사전에는 그렇게 나와 있습니다.
You're so smart, Bom.
당신은 정말 똑똑해요, 봄.
Sit.
앉다.
It's Sunday tomorrow.
내일은 일요일이에요.
-We should play soccer. -Sure.
- 우리는 축구를 해야 해요. -확신하는.
Hey, Mom.
안녕, 엄마.
Come home once in a while.
가끔 집에 오세요.
You're not saving the country, so you can afford to visit your parents.
나라를 구하는 게 아니고 그래서 당신은 부모님을 방문할 여유가 있습니다.
I've been a little busy.
좀 바빴어요.
By the way,
그런데,
do kids easily get bruises on their arms and legs?
아이들이 쉽게 멍이 들까? 팔과 다리에?
Keum-bo.
금보.
Don't worry about other people's kids.
다른 사람의 아이들에 대해 걱정하지 마십시오.
Worry about getting married yourself!
혼자 결혼하는 것에 대해 걱정하세요!
Hey.
여기요.
You don't have a name or a home?
이름도 없고 집도 없나요?
Are you a beggar?
당신은 거지입니까?
Even a beggar would have a name.
거지에게도 이름이 있을 것이다.
I'm holding back right now.
지금은 참고 있어요.
And what happens if you don't, beggar?
그렇지 않으면 어떻게 됩니까, 거지?
Hey! You horrible brats!
여기요! 이 끔찍한 놈들아!
Go! Run!
가다! 달리다!
You little…
너 좀…
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Why were those kids being mean to you?
그 아이들은 왜 당신에게 못되게 굴었나요?
I can't tell them I live in the dorms,
기숙사에 산다고는 말할 수 없고,
so I told them my name and home were secret.
그래서 내가 그들에게 말했지 내 이름과 집은 비밀이었다.
Then they called me a weirdo.
그러자 그들은 나를 이상한 사람이라고 불렀습니다.
Do you sneak out to play every day
매일 몰래 나가서 놀아?
after the aunties go to work?
이모들 출근하고 나서?
Not every day.
매일은 아닙니다.
But everyone has secrets.
하지만 누구에게나 비밀은 있습니다.
You have one too.
당신도 하나 가지고 있습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Eat up.
먹어라.
KIM MI-SOOK: WORKING SATURDAY AFTERNOON TOO
김미숙: 토요일 오후에도 근무
Oh my god.
맙소사.
Mi-sook would be so upset if she heard this.
미숙이 너무 속상할 것 같아 만약 그녀가 이 말을 들었다면.
It can't be easy for Bom to be inside all day.
봄에게는 쉽지 않을 거예요 하루 종일 안에 있어야 해요.
She's alone all day.
그녀는 하루 종일 혼자입니다.
We should give them a good scolding.
우리는 그들을 잘 꾸짖어야 합니다.
-Us? -Scold who?
-우리를? -누구를 꾸짖나요?
Hey!
여기요!
I told you beggars aren't allowed at the playground!
내가 말했잖아, 거지는 출입금지야 놀이터에서!
Hey now.
안녕하세요.
Kiddos, do you own the playground?
꼬마 여러분, 놀이터를 소유하고 있나요?
You should be nice to each other.
서로에게 친절해야 합니다.
You can't play favorites and bully others already.
즐겨찾기를 재생할 수 없습니다. 이미 다른 사람을 괴롭히고 있어요.
-Think of the country's future. -Whatever.
-나라의 미래를 생각해보세요. -무엇이든.
Who are you ladies to be butting in?
당신들은 누구에게 말을 걸고 있습니까?
We're Bom's aunties!
우리는 봄이의 이모들이에요!
So what?
그래서 뭐?
I guess she really has no mom.
정말 엄마가 없는 것 같아요.
That's not true!
그것은 사실이 아닙니다!
I guess it's true then.
그렇다면 그게 사실인 것 같아요.
My lady, it's time to go home now.
아가씨, 이제 집에 갈 시간이에요.
Wait, that's the new doll that just came out.
잠깐만요, 그거 새 인형이에요 방금 나온 것입니다.
It's the one I wanted.
내가 원했던 것이 바로 그것이다.
My dad wouldn't buy me one because it was too expensive.
아빠는 나한테 하나 사주지 않을 거야 너무 비쌌기 때문이다.
Be nice.
친절하세요.
All it took was a "my lady" to make her into some rich family's kid.
필요한 건 "나의 여자"뿐이었어 그녀를 부유한 집의 아이로 만들기 위해.
Bom, did it feel good?
봄, 기분 좋았어?
Yeah, I felt like a princess.
응, 공주가 된 기분이었어.
Of course, you're a princess.
물론, 당신은 공주입니다.
It's once again our duty to finish these skewers today.
다시 한 번 우리의 의무야 오늘 이 꼬치를 끝내려고요.
Fifty is too much. We still have thirty to go.
50은 너무 많아요. 아직 30일이 남았습니다.
You promised you wouldn't go outside.
밖에 나가지 않겠다고 약속했잖아.
I'm sorry, Mommy.
미안해요, 엄마.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Bom, why aren't you sleeping?
봄아 왜 안 자?
Auntie Eun-joo got you the pretty doll.
은주 아주머니가 예쁜 인형을 사주셨어요.
Why are you playing with these paper dolls?
왜 놀아? 이 종이 인형으로?
These have been my friends for a long time.
이들은 내 친구들이었어 오랫동안.
I see.
알겠어요.
We should build a house for your friends.
우리는 당신의 친구들을 위해 집을 지어야 합니다.
A sturdy one too.
그것도 튼튼한 것.
This sketchbook paper should be sturdy enough.
이 스케치북 종이 충분히 튼튼해야 합니다.
Pink.
분홍색.
A pink that's as pretty as you, Bom.
봄만큼 예쁜 핑크.
Let's first color the walls…
먼저 벽을 색칠해 볼까요...
-Ta-da. -Wow, how pretty.
-짜-다. -와, 정말 예쁘네요.
Let's draw her a necklace too.
그녀에게도 목걸이를 그려보자.
CORPORATE CARD RECEIPTS
법인카드 영수증
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Hello, sir. Is my car ready?
안녕하세요, 선생님. 내 차가 준비됐나요?
All right. I'll pick it up after work today.
괜찮은. 오늘 퇴근 후에 찾으러 갈게요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
HORANG AUTO REPAIR SHOP
호랑자동차정비점
Come on in.
들어오세요.
I left the keys in the car.
열쇠를 차에 두고 왔어요.
You're all set.
모든 준비가 완료되었습니다.
Here you go.
여기요.
Let's see here.
여기서 봅시다.
Do you do vehicle inspections too?
차량검사도 하시나요?
Here?
여기?
We don't.
우리는 그렇지 않습니다.
They don't pay much.
그들은 많이 지불하지 않습니다.
But you did one last July.
그런데 당신은 지난 7월에 한 번 했죠.
Do you also do repairs yourself?
직접 수리도 하시나요?
The brakes were faulty.
브레이크에 결함이 있었습니다.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
나는 당신이 무슨 말을하는지 전혀 모르겠어요.
Do you want some coffee?
커피 좀 마실래?
Hey!
여기요!
No! Don't come any closer!
아니요! 더 이상 가까이 오지 마세요!
-What's going on? -Stop right there!
- 무슨 일이에요? - 거기 멈춰!
Damn it!
젠장!
Come on, let's just talk it out!
자, 그냥 얘기해보자!
I'm here to talk.
나는 이야기하러 왔습니다.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Who sent you?
누가 당신을 보냈나요?
I just came on my own.
방금 나 혼자 왔어.
What's your deal? Stop!
당신의 거래는 무엇입니까? 멈추다!
Hold on!
기다리다!
Damn it.
젠장.
I got you.
나는 당신을 얻었다.
Man, that hurts.
아저씨, 그거 아파요.
Hey, get in!
이봐, 들어가!
Get away from me!
나에게서 떨어져!
Hey! Get them!
여기요! 가져와!
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Did you follow me?
나를 따라왔나요?
Why?
왜?
You forgot to sign something for approval, so I had to follow you.
승인을 위해 서명하는 것을 잊어버렸습니다. 그래서 나는 당신을 따라야 했어요.
Don't lie to me!
나에게 거짓말하지 마세요!
Okay.
좋아요.
Let's play the truth game.
진실게임을 해보자.
I have a lot of questions right now.
지금은 질문이 많습니다.
Why was this document in your possession?
이 문서를 귀하가 소유한 이유는 무엇입니까?
And why were you at the auto shop in question?
그리고 당신은 왜 그랬나요? 문제의 자동차 정비소에서요?
You get to ask?
물어볼 수 있나요?
Not me?
나 말고?
-I don't know why you have this-- -Answer my question.
-이런 걸 왜 가지고 있는지 모르겠어요-- - 내 질문에 답해주세요.
If it weren't for me back there, you would've been knocked out.
그 곳에 내가 없었다면, 당신은 기절했을 것입니다.
Yes, thank you for that.
네, 감사합니다.
Fine.
괜찮은.
I've been investigating my uncle's accident. Satisfied?
나는 조사를 해왔다 삼촌의 사고. 만족하는?
We still have our Nora.
우리에겐 아직 노라(Nora)가 있습니다.
I had to be here as her mother.
나는 그녀의 어머니로서 여기에 있어야만 했습니다.
After all, our Nora
결국 우리 노라
is the chairman's only child now.
지금은 회장의 외동아들이에요.
You were kicked out of here ages ago.
당신은 오래 전에 여기서 쫓겨났습니다.
I was never kicked out. I walked out on my own.
저는 쫓겨난 적이 없습니다. 나는 스스로 나갔다.
Even after his funeral mass,
그의 장례식이 끝난 후에도
not a single person mourned his death.
단 한 사람도 그의 죽음을 애도하지 않았습니다.
If Nora survives
노라가 살아남는다면
the three-month probationary period
3개월의 수습 기간
and becomes a full-time employee at Hanmin Investment & Securities,
그리고 정규직이 됩니다 한민투자증권에서
then I'll let you inherit the shares of the company
그럼 너한테 물려줄게 회사의 주식
that I intended to pass down to Myeong-hwi.
내가 물려주려고 했던 것 명휘에게.
My goodness. Nora.
이럴 수가. 노라.
But, sir.
하지만 선생님.
I'd known that my family was dysfunctional at best, but…
나는 내 가족이 기껏해야 기능 장애가 있었지만…
Chief.
수석.
We're hoping you close the case as soon as possible.
우리는 당신이 사건을 종결하길 바라고 있어요 가능한 한 빨리.
The chairman doesn't want
회장은 원하지 않는다
any further investigation into President Kang's accident.
추가 조사 강회장의 사고.
That's right.
좋아요.
Please take care of it.
잘 부탁드립니다.
POLICE ID
경찰 ID
According to the police officer,
경찰 관계자에 따르면,
evidence proving my uncle's brakes were intentionally tampered with
삼촌의 브레이크를 증명하는 증거 고의적으로 조작되었습니다
had been left out of the report.
보고서에서 제외되었습니다.
For some reason, his car was taken
무슨 이유에서인지 그의 차를 빼앗겼다
to an unfamiliar auto shop for inspection the day before his accident.
점검을 위해 낯선 자동차 정비소에 사고 전날.
It was the one we just escaped from,
방금 우리가 탈출한 사람이었어.
Horang Auto Repair Shop.
호랑자동차정비소.
Who made that change?
누가 그런 변화를 만들었나요?
Was it
그랬나요?
Go Bok-hee?
고복희?
It wasn't Ms. Go.
고씨가 아니었어요.
Wait, did Ms. Song ask you to tail me?
잠깐, 송씨가 나한테 미행하라고 했나?
No.
아니요.
Do you suspect her?
그녀를 의심하시나요?
My uncle's driver at the time claimed he just did as he was told.
당시 삼촌의 운전기사 자신은 시키는 대로 했을 뿐이라고 주장했다.
But he never told me who it was and went into hiding.
하지만 그는 그 사람이 누구인지 나에게 말해주지 않았어 그리고 숨어 들어갔다.
Why are you telling me all this?
왜 나한테 이런 걸 다 말하는 거야?
What if I tell people?
사람들에게 말하면 어떻게 되나요?
Because I'm lonely.
왜냐하면 나는 외롭기 때문이다.
You're the first person to ask about it.
그것에 대해 질문한 사람은 당신이 처음입니다.
You probably don't know anything about my uncle,
아마 모르실 거예요 삼촌에 관한 건 뭐든지,
but I just…
하지만 난 그냥…
I just wanted to tell someone.
그냥 누군가에게 말하고 싶었어요.
Also, I'm the chairman's only grandson, and you're an entry-level minion.
그리고 저는 회장님의 유일한 손자입니다. 그리고 당신은 초급 미니언입니다.
Who do you think people will believe?
사람들이 누구를 믿을 것이라고 생각합니까?
I'm not worried.
나는 걱정하지 않는다.
Look at you being all elitist.
당신이 모두 엘리트주의자인 걸 보세요.
That's just how the world works.
그것이 바로 세상이 작동하는 방식입니다.
After all, I have more real-world experience than you.
결국 나는 당신보다 실제 경험이 더 많습니다.
I don't think there's one sincere person in this company.
내 생각엔 없는 것 같아 이 회사에 성실한 사람이 한 명 있어요.
There's no sincerity,
진심이 하나도 없네
just loads of secrets.
그냥 비밀이 많아요.
Hey.
여기요.
A few days ago,
며칠 전,
some spoiled brat
좀 버릇없는 놈
came by for an oil change with his sports car.
오일 교환을 위해 방문했습니다 그의 스포츠카와 함께.
And today,
그리고 오늘,
he said something strange to me.
그 사람이 나한테 이상한 말을 했어요.
What did he say?
그가 뭐라고 말했습니까?
He asked…
그는 물었다…
if I broke someone's brakes in July.
내가 7월에 누군가의 브레이크를 부러뜨렸다면.
Ms. Song.
송 씨.
He was
그는
about 180 cm tall.
키 약 180cm.
He was young, with a handsome face.
그는 젊고 잘생긴 얼굴을 가지고 있었습니다.
And he had black eyes.
그리고 그는 검은 눈을 가지고 있었습니다.
Noted.
유명한.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'll follow up with an additional assignment soon.
후속 조치를 취하겠습니다. 곧 추가 과제가 있습니다.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
PERSONAL DETAILS SO GYEONG-DONG
개인정보 소경동
BANG JIN-MOK
방진목
PERSONAL DETAILS CHA JUNG-IL
개인정보 차정일
ALBERT OH
앨버트 오
PERSONAL DETAILS GO BOK-HEE
개인정보 고복희
Should we report yesterday's incident to the police?
신고할까 어제 경찰에 사건이 있었나요?
No. How would I trust them?
아니요. 어떻게 그들을 믿겠습니까?
Are you giving up now?
이제 포기하시나요?
Are you free tonight?
오늘 밤에 시간 있어?
What?
무엇?
FATEFUL ENCOUNTERS VIDEO & BOOK RENTALS
운명적인 만남 비디오 및 도서 대여
MUST BE 19 OR OVER TO RENT THRILLER
임대하려면 19세 이상이어야 합니다. 스릴러
Two heads are better than one.
머리 두 개가 하나보다 낫습니다.
Ms. Hong.
홍 선생님.
You've got grit.
당신은 투지가 있습니다.
Let's call it tenacity.
그것을 끈기라고 부르자.
That's the exact opposite of me.
그것은 나와 정반대입니다.
All I've ever done is give up.
내가 한 일은 포기뿐이었다.
When I was in film school,
제가 영화학교에 다닐 때,
I was always writing screenplays,
늘 시나리오를 쓰고 있었는데,
but I never finished a single one.
하지만 나는 단 하나도 끝내지 못했습니다.
I started out strong,
힘차게 시작했지만
but I gave up midway, worried the ending would be lame.
하지만 도중에 포기했고, 결말이 허무할까봐 걱정된다.
But now,
하지만 지금은,
I fear
나는 두려워한다
the ending to this storyline will be even more infuriating.
이 이야기의 결말 더욱 짜증이 날 것입니다.
So I'll stop here.
그래서 여기서 멈추겠습니다.
But you watch every videotape through to the end credits.
하지만 넌 비디오테이프를 다 보잖아 엔딩크레딧까지.
You should see this through too.
이것도 꿰뚫어 봐야 합니다.
Shall we go somewhere more private?
좀 더 프라이빗한 곳으로 갈까요?
I don't want
나는 원하지 않는다
the same ending as my uncle.
내 삼촌과 같은 결말.
They might succeed in taking me out quietly next time.
그들은 성공할 수도 있다 다음엔 조용히 데리고 나갈게.
I need someone to back me up.
나를 뒷받침해 줄 사람이 필요해요.
And even better if they can save me before that happens.
그리고 그들이 나를 구할 수 있다면 더욱 좋겠지 그 일이 일어나기 전에.
You got the right person for the job.
당신은 그 일에 적합한 사람을 찾았습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Everything I'm about to say is purely fictional.
내가 말하려는 모든 것 순전히 허구입니다.
Is there no screenplay?
각본은 없나요?
Neither my grandfather nor the audit team can raid my mind.
할아버지도 아니고 감사팀도 내 마음을 습격할 수 없습니다.
Early in the morning on July 22nd,
7월 22일 이른 아침,
my uncle got into a car accident on his way to work.
내 삼촌이 교통사고를 당했어 출근하는 길에.
Later that morning,
그날 아침 늦게,
the prosecutors seized all the files and computers on the 12th floor
검찰이 모든 파일을 압수했다 그리고 12층에 컴퓨터가 있어요
where his office was.
그의 사무실이 있던 곳.
They did.
그랬어요.
If my grandfather is right and my uncle was a traitor,
할아버지 말이 맞다면 그리고 내 삼촌은 배신자였지
my uncle would've left
내 삼촌은 떠났을 거야
the whistleblower evidence in his office before he went home the night before.
그의 사무실에 있는 내부 고발자 증거 그 전날 밤 집에 가기 전에.
You know, as a sort of promise.
일종의 약속으로요.
I know that because it was my idea.
나는 그것이 내 생각이었기 때문에 그것을 안다.
It was your idea?
당신 생각이었나요?
It was a storyline in one of my unfinished screenplays.
줄거리였습니다 내 미완성 각본 중 하나에서요.
My uncle read it and called it awful,
삼촌이 그걸 읽고 끔찍하다고 하더군요.
but he wanted to steal just that part.
하지만 그는 그 부분만 훔치고 싶었어요.
If the prosecutors
만약 검찰이
had found something, they would've taken action.
뭔가를 발견했고, 그들은 조치를 취했을 것입니다.
But they didn't.
하지만 그들은 그렇지 않았습니다.
It doesn't seem like the company covered it up,
아닌 것 같아 회사에서 은폐했는데
either.
어느 쪽이든.
What if President Kang's aide
강 대통령 측근이라면?
delivered the whistleblower evidence to the 12th floor,
제보자 증거를 전달했다 12층까지,
only for a third party to snatch it up?
제3자가 빼앗을 수만 있나요?
If it was someone who could enter his office
누군가였다면 누가 그의 사무실에 들어갈 수 있었나요?
without attracting attention,
관심을 끌지 못한 채,
then it's possible.
그렇다면 가능합니다.
You had such access.
당신은 그런 접근권을 가지고있었습니다.
Me?
나?
No.
아니요.
Not me, but that woman in your life.
내가 아니라 당신 인생의 그 여자입니다.
Go Bok-hee.
고복희.
The cart.
카트.
I tried to see if I could get something out of her,
보려고 했는데 내가 그녀에게서 뭔가를 얻을 수 있다면,
but I got nothing.
하지만 나는 아무것도 얻지 못했습니다.
Hold on a second.
잠깐만요.
There's someone else.
다른 사람이 있어요.
Who?
WHO?
I'll check and let you know.
확인해 보고 알려드리겠습니다.
-You should go home. -What about you?
- 집에 가야 해요. -당신은 어때요?
It's already past curfew at the dorms.
벌써 기숙사 통금 시간이 지났어요.
I've already got three demerit points, so I need to tread carefully.
벌써 벌점 3점을 받았어요. 그래서 조심해서 밟아야 해요.
Then I'm staying here.
그럼 난 여기 남을게.
Can't you just go?
그냥 가면 안 돼요?
You won't tell me who it is, and you want to check on your own.
당신은 그 사람이 누구인지 나에게 말하지 않을 것입니다. 그리고 당신은 스스로 확인하고 싶습니다.
How can I just leave you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 떠날 수 있나요?
Fine.
괜찮은.
We'll check together at 5 a.m.
오전 5시에 함께 확인하겠습니다.
Okay.
알았어.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-Just another busy day ahead. -Have a good day.
- 앞으로 또 바쁜 하루가 될 것 같아요. -좋은 하루 보내세요.
Oh gosh! You scared me.
맙소사! 당신은 나를 겁주었어요.
You're the cleaning lady from that day.
당신은 그날부터 청소 아줌마입니다.
The chairman's grandson?
회장 손자?
That's right, ma'am.
그렇죠, 부인.
You remember the chairman's grandson, right?
당신은 기억한다 회장 손자 맞죠?
I made a big mistake the other day.
나는 지난번에 큰 실수를 저질렀습니다.
I'm terribly sorry.
정말 죄송합니다.
Why don't we chat some more in the office?
사무실에서 좀 더 이야기 나누는 게 어때요?
I fear our young master…
나는 우리 젊은 주인이 두렵다…
I mean, the division manager might find standing exhausting.
즉, 부서장 서 있으면 지칠 수도 있습니다.
My legs do hurt a bit. Shall we go inside and chat some more?
다리가 좀 아프긴 해요. 안으로 들어가서 좀 더 이야기를 나눠볼까요?
But I have to finish cleaning the president's office within 30 minutes.
하지만 청소를 끝내야 해 30분 안에 대통령 집무실로 가세요.
Ms. Hong will help you with the cleaning.
홍 선생님이 청소를 도와드릴 거예요.
I'll remain seated.
저는 계속 앉아 있을게요.
Right, Ms. Hong?
그렇죠, 홍 선생님?
That's right.
좋아요.
The new president is very tidy,
신임회장은 매우 깔끔하다.
so there isn't much to clean.
그래서 청소할 게 별로 없어요.
Yes, he's one tidy person.
응, 그 사람은 깔끔한 사람이야.
By the way, what did you want to talk to me about?
그건 그렇고, 나한테 무슨 얘기하고 싶었어?
Ma'am, do you remember what you did on July 22nd,
부인, 기억하시나요? 7월 22일에 무엇을 했는지,
on the day of the late president's accident?
당일에 고 대통령의 사고?
Of course. It was a complete mess.
물론. 그것은 완전히 엉망이었습니다.
The prosecutors stormed in to seize everything in sight.
검찰이 들이닥쳤다. 눈에 보이는 모든 것을 포착합니다.
You cleaned this office that morning as well, right?
이 사무실을 청소하셨군요 그날 아침에도 그랬죠?
Of course, I did.
물론 그렇습니다.
-Hello there. -Hello.
-안녕. -안녕하세요.
The president's pen…
대통령의 만년필…
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
I remember his assistant came in early that day too.
그의 조수가 생각난다 그날도 일찍 왔어.
I heard the chairman had called for an emergency meeting.
회장님이 그러셨다고 들었는데 긴급회의를 소집했다.
-I can get that. -Sorry.
-그건 알 수 있어요. -죄송합니다.
She was all over the place.
그녀는 곳곳에 있었습니다.
The files are usually marked with the floor they came from.
파일은 일반적으로 표시됩니다 그들이 나온 바닥과 함께.
That's right.
좋아요.
She took the notebook with the sticker on the cover.
그녀는 수첩을 가져갔다 표지에 스티커가 붙어있습니다.
Have a good day.
좋은 하루 보내세요.
You too.
너도.
A sticker?
스티커?
What's your deal? Don't dig through my stuff!
당신의 거래는 무엇입니까? 내 물건을 뒤져보지 마세요!
Wait, I'm not…
잠깐만, 난 아니야…
No, hold on.
아니, 잠깐만요.
What…
뭐…
Just another sleepless night.
또 잠 못 이루는 밤이군요.
No way.
안 돼요.
Did she stay out?
그 사람은 밖에 있었나요?
Where's that notebook?
그 노트는 어디 있지?
What notebook?
무슨 노트북?
The notebook with the sticker you accused me of stealing.
스티커가 붙은 노트 당신은 나를 도둑질했다고 비난했습니다.
I don't know, maybe I left it at the office?
나는 모른다. 어쩌면 사무실에 두고 온 것 아닐까?
It's not at your desk. I already checked.
그것은 당신 책상에 없습니다. 나는 이미 확인했다.
You went through my desk?
내 책상을 뒤졌어?
Have you lost your mind?
정신을 잃었나요?
You figured it out after you saw that ledger
당신은 그것을 알아 냈습니다 그 장부를 본 후에
where the easy money was buried.
쉽게 얻은 돈이 묻힌 곳.
Hey!
여기요!
What's your deal?
당신의 거래는 무엇입니까?
Are you with the police? The secret service?
경찰과 함께 있나요? 비밀 서비스?
What gives you the right to do this?
무엇이 당신에게 이런 일을 할 수 있는 권리를 주나요?
Stop it!
그만해요!
Oh no.
안 돼.
We should do something.
뭔가를 해야 해요.
Damn it.
젠장.
Where's the magazine that I put here?
내가 여기에 넣어둔 잡지는 어디에 있나요?
-Magazine? -I threw it out.
-잡지? - 버렸어요.
-You threw it out?
- 버렸어요?
Yeah. It was dorm clean-out day yesterday.
응. 어제는 기숙사 대청소를 하는 날이었습니다.
Great.
엄청난.
WOMEN'S MAGAZINE
여성 매거진
AUGUST 1997, SUMMER EDITION
1997년 8월, 여름 에디션
I tossed it because it was the August summer issue.
버렸으니까요 8월 여름호였어요.
Are you crazy? Why would you throw that out?
제정신이에요? 그걸 왜 버릴까요?
You hid the ledger inside a magazine?
장부를 잡지 속에 숨겼나요?
Magazines are made out of paper…
잡지는 종이로 만들어지는데...
And recycled paper ends up in the incinerator!
그리고 재활용 종이 결국 소각장에 갇히게 됩니다!
The incinerator?
소각장?
Sir, have you seen a notebook this big?
선생님, 이렇게 큰 공책 본 적 있나요?
There's a dog sticker in the bottom-right corner.
강아지 스티커가 있어요 오른쪽 하단에 있습니다.
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
Mister.
아저씨.
Where's the third-floor paper waste from yesterday's clean-out?
3층 종이 쓰레기는 어디에 있나요? 어제 청소 때문에?
Jeez, I burned it all up already.
이런, 벌써 다 태워버렸어.
See? It's all gone.
보다? 모두 사라졌습니다.
You should've come sooner.
좀 더 일찍 왔어야 했는데.
Where did you get that notebook from?
그 노트는 어디서 났어요?
I just…
난 그냥…
I just found it somewhere.
방금 어딘가에서 찾았어요.
I told you last time
지난번에 말했잖아
that there's easy money at the company.
회사에 쉽게 돈이 있다는 것.
This would've never happened if we joined forces then.
이런 일은 절대 일어나지 않았을 거야 그때 우리가 힘을 합친다면.
You found the notebook?
노트를 찾았나요?
You took it from the president's office.
대통령 집무실에서 가져오셨어요.
Did you take it knowing about the raid?
습격에 대해 알고 가져갔나요?
Who told you to?
누가 말했지?
Listen, I wouldn't feel this wronged if I'd been paid something.
들어봐, 난 이게 잘못됐다고 생각하지 않을 거야 내가 뭔가를 받았더라면.
It was clearly a slush fund ledger.
그것은 분명히 비자금 장부였습니다.
The president had passed away,
대통령이 세상을 떠났고,
so how could I return it not knowing who'd sent it from the seventh floor?
그럼 내가 어떻게 그걸 모르고 돌려줄 수 있겠어? 누가 7층에서 보냈지?
The seventh floor?
7층?
Yes, the seventh floor.
네, 7층이에요.
That's what the note on it said,
그 메모에는 이렇게 적혀 있었습니다.
with no division name.
부서 이름이 없습니다.
Have a good day.
좋은 하루 보내세요.
You too.
너도.
If it's the seventh floor, it's either Trading, Research…
7층이라면, 거래든 연구든…
or the Risk Management Division.
또는 위험 관리 부서.
What the hell is her deal?
도대체 그녀의 거래는 무엇입니까?
There's a dog sticker in the bottom-right corner.
강아지 스티커가 있어요 오른쪽 하단에 있습니다.
I burned it up already.
이미 태워버렸어요.
The president had passed away,
대통령이 세상을 떠났고,
so how could I return it not knowing who'd sent it from the seventh floor?
그럼 내가 어떻게 그걸 모르고 돌려줄 수 있겠어? 누가 7층에서 보냈지?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I'd like to ask why you ran out this morning
나는 묻고 싶다 오늘 아침에 왜 나갔어?
and what you're agonizing over now, if possible.
그리고 당신은 무엇입니까 가능하다면 지금 고민 중입니다.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
After all, we're on the same team,
결국 우리는 같은 팀이니까
and we're partners.
그리고 우리는 파트너예요.
I can wait.
기다릴 수 있어요.
You let the slush fund ledger burn before we even laid eyes on it?
비자금 장부를 불태워버리다니 우리가 보기도 전에요?
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
There's no point in postponing it.
미뤄봐도 소용이 없습니다.
Resign and come back immediately!
사임하고 즉시 복귀하라!
But at least we know now that it came from the seventh--
하지만 적어도 우리는 지금 알고 있어요 일곱 번째 날부터 온 거라고--
TO: YEHPPEE
받는 사람: 예피
STATUS: UNREAD
상태: 읽지 않음
I have infiltrated Hanmin.
한민에 잠입했어요.
Hello, Yehppee. This is Hong Keum-bo.
안녕하세요, 예피입니다. 홍금보입니다.
In order to meet you in person,
고객님을 직접 만나 뵙기 위해,
I've taken someone else's identity to get a job in Hanmin.
다른 사람의 신분을 도용했어요 한민에 취직하려고
I heard that you also work on the seventh floor.
너도 일한다고 들었어 7층에.
I'd like to meet you.
나는 당신을 만나고 싶습니다.
I'll be awaiting your reply.
귀하의 답변을 기다리겠습니다.
SEND
보내기
SUBJECT: I HAVE INFILTRATED HANMIN
제목: 한민에 잠입했습니다
SENDING…
보내는 중…
YOUR MAIL HAS BEEN SENT
귀하의 메일이 전송되었습니다
Hey, it's me.
안녕하세요. 나예요.
Can you look up a plate for me?
접시 좀 찾아주실 수 있나요?
"Seoul 1. B2727."
"서울 1. B2727."
Thanks.
감사해요.
ALL MAIL
모든 메일
STATUS: READ
상태: 읽음
INBOX
받은 편지함
Meet me at nine o'clock tonight,
오늘 밤 아홉시에 만나요
at the same place you used to meet with President Kang.
같은 장소에서 강 회장님을 만나본 적이 있잖아요.
It's working fine.
잘 작동합니다.
This needs your signature.
여기에는 귀하의 서명이 필요합니다.
No, "E" is the issue. The "E" key isn't working.
아니요, "E"가 문제입니다. "E" 키가 작동하지 않습니다.
Pay attention.
주의하세요.
-Hello.
-안녕하세요.
CHA JUNG-IL, BANG JIN-MOK
차정일, 방진목
I'm on my way to meet Yehppee.
예피를 만나러 가는 중이에요.
I'll report back when I'm done.
끝나면 다시 보고하겠습니다.
Hey, who the hell are you to meddle in Go Bok-hee's family affairs?
야, 너 도대체 누구야? 고복희 집안일에 간섭하려고?
-Let go of me. -Damn it.
-나를 놓아주세요. -젠장.
Why you little…
왜 꼬마야...
I told you, he punched me.
내가 말했잖아, 그 사람이 날 때렸어.
-Damn it. -Get in there.
-젠장. - 거기 들어가세요.
Damn it.
젠장.
Yehppee?
응?
Over here!
여기요!
Yehp…
응…
Wait. Wait a minute!
기다리다. 잠깐 기다려요!
Wait!
기다리다!
One, two.
하나, 둘.
Move!
이동하다!
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
INVESTMENT TRUST PRODUCT
투자신탁상품
I have no choice now.
이제 선택의 여지가 없습니다.
I'll just have to force an introduction.
강제로 소개를 해야겠습니다.
You're here early.
일찍 오셨군요.
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요.
Coffee, Mr. Bang?
커피요, 방 선생님?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
By the way, why did you run off last night?
그건 그렇고, 어젯밤에 왜 도망갔어?
You made me run by the river for quite some time.
당신은 나를 강으로 뛰게 만들었어요 꽤 오랫동안.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I knew it was you.
나는 그것이 당신이라는 것을 알았습니다.
Yehppee was able to keep his face hidden,
예피는 얼굴을 숨길 수 있었고,
but he gave away something else.
하지만 그는 다른 것을 포기했습니다.
What?
무엇?
You already know, Yehppee.
넌 이미 알고 있잖아, 예피.
Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보.
UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
Who's that in the photo?
사진 속 저 사람은 누구죠?
That's my eldest daughter.
그 사람은 내 큰 딸이에요.
Ms. Kim Mi-sook is the top salesperson.
김미숙씨는 영업사원 1위다.
Hong Keum-bo? You'd better not mess up this time.
홍금보? 이번에는 엉망으로 만들지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Something feels off with all of it.
모든 것이 뭔가 기분이 좋지 않습니다.
You should take her back immediately.
즉시 그녀를 다시 데려가야 합니다.
So you knew about it going in.
그래서 당신은 그것이 들어가는 것을 알고있었습니다.
Just hand over the materials, and we'll take care of the rest.
재료만 건네주고, 나머지는 우리가 처리하겠습니다.
An emergency executive meeting?
긴급 임원회의요?
Did you call the Ministry of Finance and Economy?
전화하셨나요? 재정경제부요?
There's no issue with the slush fund, is there?
문제없어요 비자금으로요?
Hey, Hong. We're in big trouble.
안녕, 홍. 우리는 큰 문제에 빠졌습니다.
What are you doing here, Ms. Hong Jang-mi?
홍장미씨 여기서 뭐하세요?
Subtitle translation by: Justin S. Kim
자막 번역: Justin S. Kim